Now we'll call the order of the regular meeting of the Miami City Council for Monday November 1st, 2021, and number 2,
Proclamation declaring November 9th, 2021 as Barbara Smith, Day, in Miami, and she's here today with us, and she was awarded, I had it here, it wasn't on the Proclamation, so I had looked it up here to make sure
for the O'Connor Arts Council, Governor's Award, is that correct, and that's a pretty big achievement, and you've done a lot of things here in Miami, you've taught a lot of students here in Miami,
and you've been here a long time and we appreciate all your input that you've had on everything, I see you've worked with the Coleman, I know you do a lot of stuff, so we appreciate that, and I got a proclamation here, I want to give to you.
I want to really say one thing, it's been a pleasure, each and every job I've had, and I've had a whole lot of different jobs from state president, the teacher's association to all my years of coaching my speech team and taking those kids everywhere, and just working for goals that would make life better in general, and my life will also be, I would do something that makes the positive difference, and I try to instill it in my students,
but no one person can ever accomplish much of anything, we know that, we have to have the right goals, the right dreams, and we have to have the right people that will follow our leadership, and I think that's the lesson,
everyone of you has this learning and it all has already learned because you are in positions of leadership, and I'm so deeply appreciate this, I was really thinking, well, I'm really getting a hold down, I'm not able to do all this stuff, even though I did kind of come out and direct a little play, a couple of ways to come up with the Coleman videos, but anyway, thank you so much, and I want to thank the citizens of Miami and all the people I've worked with and all of my hundreds of students,
who are having a special reunion this summer, the speech kids reunion, because we're still a family, and I think of our community as a family, we have all kinds of relatives, and we have to work with the good of all, so I appreciate you, and I certainly appreciate this proclamation, thank you so much.
Number three public input around scheduled personal differences we have now for action item
The staff recommends we approve items five three seven
Action item resolution CC 2020
Best 14 for bridge inspection responsible to the city of my own
Yes, so this is for us to hire guy engineering does the county's bridge inspections
And so they previously have done our bridge inspections for the bridges in my amma
So this is for them to come in and do the bridge inspections
We have seven bridges they inspect I can name them off you guys want
But and this is paid for through this date
I think they get federal transportation money to pay for it so I'm the do the inspection. I'll give us a report
And then we'll present to the council
Then we'll go fix it. I mean any issues
The will fix and so it's that's down every two years
So you have to think how to go from once I do others
So you have central
You have a rockdale
Then you would have
I'm street and then if you turn left you'd have 20 second both sides
And then you would have the one on the street where E and D come together and then you would have one out by
Setter right there with us to mask them across. Yes
Car Creek state expected now they rocked out this this
Steve owns they want to see about the state's expected
Then the one by
A hardware
Yes, I would be sitting selected to it's it's interesting important if you're an engineer
I mean if you find interesting all the little things. They have on it
It's a huge training that we're so we watch the chiefs game. So he's yeah, I'm out of short time
He's got his own timer
So you need motion from us. Yes, sir. Second. Hi
Thank you. Thank you. I'm an eye on action item mayors nomination to a point
Megan Dory to library board turn to expire one
3.3. 10, another new business of India is risen since
posting this agenda 11 staff reports 12 mayor or council
community announcements that's kind of what we want and that's what Barbara was
talking about being the family and doing things together so you're out of this
good to see and that's got anything all right number 13 city manager communications
well I'd like to start by kind of piling on Brian's comments so I had the
opportunity to take the kids downtown to Main Street on Sunday for Halloween to
the sweet street trail and then the
Buhaha parade, but I had no idea what to expect when I went down there and it was really
incredible. You to turn out downtown the number of people, the number of folks that were
handing out candy and just the overall experience of people that were happy to be there and
had their kids there and strolling up an mane. I got to my son and his wife had our grand babies there
and they got to go through the Coleman and see everything. I had people up on the stage,
handing out candy and it was really phenomenal. But I was impressed and really thrilled and it made me
really proud of our town to have pulled something like that together for the kids to get together and
do that. So that was really neat. I wanted to comment on that. Additionally, this last week we had the
great deer hunt that River Bottom Sportsman and the Mid-America chapter of the Paralyzed
Veterans of America puts together and I had the honor to present them with city proclamations
for our Paralyzed veterans that were being honored this year at the great deer hunt and it was
a great banquet. They originally had scheduled as you probably know the flag raising downtown but
whether it was not permitting. So they ended up having to cancel the flag raising but they moved the
part of the events to the banquet that evening Thursday evening but I was able to attend and able to
present those proclamations at night. He was really moving. They were really, really honored to be receiving
the city's proclamations and I was able to read one of the proclamations allowed to the banquet and again
really honored to get to do that and I appreciate the council allowing me to take those proclamations
of present those and what a great event. These guys were in gals were really appreciative of what that
deer hunt offered them and the accommodations that were made for them to be able to get out and do
a unique activity like Go deer hunting. And as I hear, it's always a wonderful event. It's been
going on for many, many years now and it's extremely successful and has grown tremendously. So
neat thing also that goes on in my amulet that I didn't know anything about until I got here
have been really impressed with. And then wanted to remind everybody that next week, November 11th next
Thursday will be veterans day and the city offices will be closed that day and we also have a parade
and a main street at 5 p.m. on veterans day. So hopefully everybody can get out and get to attend that.
And then I would also like to point out to the council that we've been here in the great hall having
our meetings but given that our COVID numbers continue to to trend downward positively.
We've seen significant drops by nearly 50% since the beginning of October and since we continue to see that trend.
I'm going to be making a recommendation that we move our council meetings back to the council room.
So if any council members have any concerns, please reach out to me.
Between now and our next meeting and let me know if you feel otherwise but otherwise I'll be making that recommendation that we move back in there.
I'll second that.
I thought you might.
Other than that, that's all I have.
I'm happy to take any questions.
All right, number 14 adjourned.